Hello, welcome to class. Again, welcome. My name is David Brown and this is going to be an original combo reading writing and grammar class. I'm glad that you're all here. Have a seat everybody. Welcome.
مرحباً، أهلاً بكم في الدرس. مرة أخرى، أهلاً بكم. اسمي ديفيد براون وهذا سيكون درساً أصلياً مركباً في القراءة والكتابة والقواعد. أنا سعيد بوجودكم جميعاً هنا. تفضلوا بالجلوس جميعاً. أهلاً بكم.
Hey, Hector. How are you?
مرحباً يا هكتور (Hiktur). كيف حالك؟
Just fine. How are you?
بخير تماماً. كيف حالك أنت؟
I'm doing great. Thank you.
أنا بخير جداً. شكراً لك.
Welcome. Welcome.
أهلاً بك. أهلاً بك.
Thank you.
شكراً لك.
I see that you selected a class about arguments. Would you like to learn how to be more persuasive in today's class?
أرى أنك اخترت درساً عن الحجج (arguments). هل تود أن تتعلم كيف تكون أكثر إقناعاً في درس اليوم؟
I would like to. I would love to actually because that's a very important thing to do when you speak another language.
أود ذلك. في الواقع، أود ذلك بشدة لأن هذا أمر مهم جداً عند التحدث بلغة أخرى.
Yeah, the basic question of this is what do we want and how do we get that? And communication is the means in which we acquire the things that we want.
نعم، السؤال الأساسي في هذا هو: ماذا نريد وكيف نحصل عليه؟ والتواصل هو الوسيلة التي نكتسب بها الأشياء التي نريدها.
So learning to be persuasive is just really an amazing soft skills to learn.
لذا فإن تعلم أن تكون مقنعاً هو حقاً من المهارات الناعمة الرائعة للتعلم.
And there are procedures that we can follow in order to persuade effectively. So in today's lesson, we'll talk about persuading effectively and about some grammar reading and writing task that can help us to persuade formally.
وهناك إجراءات يمكننا اتباعها من أجل الإقناع بفعالية. لذا في درس اليوم، سنتحدث عن الإقناع بفعالية وعن بعض مهام القراءة والكتابة والقواعد التي يمكن أن تساعدنا على الإقناع بشكل رسمي.
We have this concept of cohesion and cohesion is when something is whole.
لدينا مفهوم "cohesion" (التماسك - at-tamāsuk)، والتماسك هو عندما يكون الشيء كلاً متكاملاً.
In order to make a good argument, we need to have all the parts of the argument.
لكي نقدم حجة جيدة، نحتاج إلى أن تكون لدينا جميع أجزاء الحجة.
And we also need the argument to be smooth. It has to flow. So we have cohesion and those two concepts that we'll talk about a little bit today.
ونحتاج أيضاً أن تكون الحجة سلسة. يجب أن يكون لها انسيابية (flow). لذا لدينا "cohesion" (التماسك) و "flow" (الانسيابية - al-insiyābiyyah)، وهما مفهومان سنتحدث عنهما قليلاً اليوم.
So let's explore how we can achieve this.
إذاً، دعنا نستكشف كيف يمكننا تحقيق ذلك.
So I have an image on the screen here. It says from jumbled ideas to a clear persuasive point.
لدي صورة على الشاشة هنا. تقول "من الأفكار المشوشة إلى وجهة نظر واضحة ومقنعة".
We see this guy with a messy room.
نرى هذا الرجل وغرفته فوضوية.
He's torn over curtain there.
ستارته هناك ممزقة.
And it makes it look clean there.
وهي تجعل المكان يبدو نظيفاً هناك.
It actually looks like mine.
في الواقع تبدو كغرفتي.
All right, all right.
حسناً، حسناً.
We have our arguments are like this, right?
حججنا تشبه هذا، أليس كذلك؟
Our arguments can be messy or they can be organized.
يمكن أن تكون حججنا فوضوية أو يمكن أن تكون منظمة.
And if our arguments are presented in an organized way, then we're more likely to convince people that something is true.
وإذا عُرضت حججنا بطريقة منظمة، فمن المرجح أن نقنع الناس بأن شيئاً ما صحيح.
We want to do this genuinely. How can we genuinely organize our ideas to make a persuasive point?
نريد أن نفعل هذا بصدق. كيف يمكننا أن ننظم أفكارنا بصدق لتقديم وجهة نظر مقنعة؟
Let's see if you can remember something about arguments or tell me what you think you know about persuasion.
دعنا نرى ما إذا كنت تتذكر شيئاً عن الحجج أو أخبرني بما تعتقد أنك تعرفه عن الإقناع.
What are two parts of an argument that you remember?
ما هما الجزءان من الحجة اللذان تتذكرهما؟
Remember any specific parts?
هل تتذكر أي أجزاء محددة؟
Actually, I can't remember it.
في الواقع، لا أستطيع أن أتذكر.
You know, like being so organized.
كما تعلم، مثل أن تكون منظماً جداً.
And let me see the other one.
ودعني أرى الآخر.
You said, organized.
قلتَ، منظماً.
And messy.
وفوضوياً.
Okay.
حسناً.
And the opposite will be organized, right?
والعكس سيكون منظماً، أليس كذلك؟
So being organized versus his versus messy.
إذاً أن تكون منظماً مقابل أن تكون فوضوياً.
How about the structure of an argument?
ماذا عن بنية الحجة؟
How do you argue effectively?
كيف تجادل بفعالية؟
What is something that you need to do in order to make a good argument?
ما هو الشيء الذي تحتاج إلى القيام به لتقديم حجة جيدة؟
Well, actually, I need to, I need to make it so comprehensive.
حسناً، في الواقع، أحتاج إلى، أحتاج إلى جعلها شاملة جداً.
Right? For the person that is.
أليس كذلك؟ بالنسبة للشخص المعني.
Listen to one argument. Right?
يستمع إلى حجة واحدة. أليس كذلك؟
And it has to be easy.
ويجب أن تكون سهلة.
To understand.
للفهم.
And easy to understand too.
وسهلة الفهم أيضاً.
Agreed.
أتفق معك.
So if we improve some of these aspects of grammar, like cohesion and flow, we can make it easier to understand.
لذا إذا قمنا بتحسين بعض هذه الجوانب من القواعد، مثل التماسك والانسيابية، يمكننا جعلها أسهل للفهم.
We can make it organized and not messy.
يمكننا جعلها منظمة وليست فوضوية.
And we can make it whole. We can make it comprehensive.
ويمكننا جعلها متكاملة. يمكننا جعلها شاملة.
So these are our learning objectives for today's class.
إذاً هذه هي أهدافنا التعليمية لدرس اليوم.
Can you read this first objective for us?
هل يمكنك قراءة هذا الهدف الأول لنا؟
Yeah, learning objectives for today.
نعم، أهداف التعلم لليوم.
Analyze a model argument for structure and flow.
تحليل حجة نموذجية من حيث البنية والانسيابية.
You want me to read all of them?
هل تريدني أن أقرأها كلها؟
Okay.
حسناً.
Utilize a graphic organizer to the construct arguments.
استخدام منظم بياني لبناء الحجج.
Understand how grammatical choices impact clearly.
فهم كيف تؤثر الخيارات النحوية على الوضوح.
And cohesion.
والتماسك.
Practice using transitional device says effectively.
التدرب على استخدام أدوات الربط بفعالية.
And identify and correct common errors affecting argument clearly.
وتحديد وتصحيح الأخطاء الشائعة التي تؤثر على وضوح الحجة.
Alright, let's practice two of these words here.
حسناً، دعنا نتدرب على هاتين الكلمتين هنا.
This one is pronounced repeat after me clarity, clarity.
هذه تُنطق، كرر بعدي، clarity, clarity.
Oh, clarity.
أوه، clarity.
Okay.
حسناً.
And this one is with a Jen sound, like a Z.
وهذه بصوت Jen، مثل Z.
ZJ kind of sound cohesion.
نوع من صوت ZJ، cohesion.
Cohesion and clarity.
Cohesion و clarity.
Okay.
حسناً.
Yeah, I didn't notice it was.
نعم، لم ألاحظ أنها كانت.
The word as with clear.
نفس كلمة clear.
I confuse it actually.
لقد اختلط الأمر عليّ في الواقع.
Yeah, it's related to the word clear.
نعم، إنها مرتبطة بكلمة clear.
So clear.
لذا clear.
Yeah, it's related.
نعم، إنهما مرتبطان.
The same thing.
نفس الشيء.
Right.
صحيح.
That's what I think.
هذا ما أعتقده.
Uh huh.
أهأ.
So you have clarity, which is the noun and something is clear.
إذاً لديك clarity، وهي الاسم، وشيء ما clear،
It's the adjective.
فهي الصفة.
Yeah.
نعم.
Alright.
حسناً.
So what we can start off with first is the anatomy of an argument.
إذاً ما يمكننا أن نبدأ به أولاً هو تشريح الحجة.
The different parts of an argument.
الأجزاء المختلفة للحجة.
And this is something that we can learn.
وهذا شيء يمكننا تعلمه.
And remember from the days in school, when we would write essays and things like that.
ونتذكر من أيام الدراسة، عندما كنا نكتب المقالات وأشياء من هذا القبيل.
How do you structure an essay?
كيف تبني مقالاً؟
What comes first, next, and then last, when you write?
ما الذي يأتي أولاً، ثم تالياً، ثم أخيراً، عندما تكتب؟
Let's read this part here.
دعنا نقرأ هذا الجزء هنا.
Can you read this paragraph for me?
هل يمكنك قراءة هذه الفقرة لي؟
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
A well crafted argument resembles a well engineered structure.
الحجة المتقنة تشبه البنية الهندسية الجيدة.
It requires robust components and seamless connections.
تتطلب مكونات قوية وروابط سلسة.
Cohesion ensures ideas interlinked logically.
التماسك يضمن ترابط الأفكار منطقياً.
While fluency allows the reader to navigate the argument smoothly.
بينما تسمح السلاسة للقارئ بتصفح الحجة بسلاسة.
Okay, excellent.
حسناً، ممتاز.
So I made this image here to demonstrate this idea geometrically.
لذا صنعت هذه الصورة هنا لتوضيح هذه الفكرة هندسياً.
So we have the idea that an argument is complete.
لذا لدينا فكرة أن الحجة مكتملة.
But an argument can be complete, but not flow well.
ولكن يمكن أن تكون الحجة مكتملة، ولكنها لا تنساب بشكل جيد.
An argument can have all of the parts, but they're not put together.
يمكن أن تحتوي الحجة على جميع الأجزاء، ولكنها غير مجمعة معاً.
So if we look at each stage of this, we see that it starts with a few elements that are not connected very well.
لذا إذا نظرنا إلى كل مرحلة من هذه المراحل، نرى أنها تبدأ ببضعة عناصر غير مترابطة بشكل جيد.
They're not connected via the reasoning that we need.
إنها غير مترابطة من خلال الاستدلال الذي نحتاجه.
We see that it starts to form, but it doesn't have good flow.
نرى أنها تبدأ في التكون، ولكن ليس لديها انسيابية جيدة.
And when the flow improves, we end with the perfect circle.
وعندما تتحسن الانسيابية، ننتهي بدائرة مثالية.
So this illustrates the idea of a cohesion, which is it being whole.
لذا هذا يوضح فكرة التماسك، وهو كونها كلاً متكاملاً.
The hexagon in this picture has cohesion, but it doesn't have flow.
الشكل السداسي في هذه الصورة لديه تماسك، ولكنه ليس لديه انسيابية.
This circle, on the other hand, has cohesion and has flow.
هذه الدائرة، من ناحية أخرى، لديها تماسك وانسيابية.
So how can we do that?
إذاً كيف يمكننا فعل ذلك؟
How can we structure our paragraphs and our essays?
كيف يمكننا بناء فقراتنا ومقالاتنا؟
So that it is organized that it contains all of the parts that it needs.
بحيث تكون منظمة وتحتوي على جميع الأجزاء التي تحتاجها.
And so that it transitions from one part to the next logically.
وبحيث تنتقل من جزء إلى آخر بشكل منطقي.
And if we do that right, if we do it effectively, then we have both of those elements and we strengthen our argument.
وإذا فعلنا ذلك بشكل صحيح، إذا فعلناه بفعالية، فسيكون لدينا كلا هذين العنصرين ونقوي حجتنا.
So we have these argumentative elements, the puzzle pieces, cohesion, the connective structure, and the fluency, the smooth flow between ideas.
لذا لدينا هذه العناصر الحجاجية، قطع الأحجية، التماسك، أي البنية الرابطة، والانسيابية، أي التدفق السلس بين الأفكار.
All right. So we need to remember these core components of an argument.
حسناً. لذا نحتاج إلى تذكر هذه المكونات الأساسية للحجة.
Let's read these here. Can you read these for me?
دعنا نقرأ هذه هنا. هل يمكنك قراءتها لي؟
Sure. Can I read it from the very beginning?
بالتأكيد. هل يمكنني القراءة من البداية؟
Like recall the core components of an argument, claim, actually, background, ceases,
مثل استدعاء المكونات الأساسية للحجة: الادعاء (claim - al-iddiʿāʾ)، الحقائق (facts - al-ḥaqāʾiq)، الخلفية (background - al-khalfiyyah)، الأطروحة (thesis - al-uṭrūḥah)،
topic sentences, evidence, examples, potential, rebuttal,
الجمل الرئيسية (topic sentences - al-jumal ar-raʾīsiyyah)، الأدلة (evidence - al-adillah)، الأمثلة (examples - al-amthilah)، الدحض المحتمل (potential rebuttal - ad-daḥḍ al-muḥtamal)،
and conclusion, a solid grasp of this element is foundational.
والخاتمة (conclusion - al-khātimah). الفهم الراسخ لهذه العناصر أساسي.
Very good.
جيد جداً.
So we have the claim. Another word for claim is a thesis.
إذاً لدينا "claim" (الادعاء). كلمة أخرى لـ "claim" هي "thesis" (الأطروحة).
We have the background, which is the context of what we're talking about.
لدينا "background" (الخلفية)، وهي سياق ما نتحدث عنه.
If we start talking and we start arguing, but nobody knows what we're talking about with the background of it, then it's not clear.
إذا بدأنا الحديث وبدأنا الجدال، ولكن لا أحد يعرف ما نتحدث عنه أو خلفيته، فلن يكون الأمر واضحاً.
So we start with a claim.
لذا نبدأ بـ "claim" (الادعاء).
We can give us some background information about that.
يمكننا تقديم بعض المعلومات الأساسية حول ذلك.
And then we have our thesis statement.
ثم لدينا "thesis statement" (بيان الأطروحة).
This is a thesis statement that is basically the main argument of the entire thing we're trying to convince the other person to believe.
هذا بيان أطروحة وهو بشكل أساسي الحجة الرئيسية للشيء بأكمله الذي نحاول إقناع الشخص الآخر بتصديقه.
So to persuade is to convince someone else to believe something.
لذا فإن الإقناع هو إقناع شخص آخر بتصديق شيء ما.